A Guide to the Virginia O'Neill Architectural Collection, 1937-1965
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Virginia O'Neill Architectural Collection, 1937-1965
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2006-010
10 folders; 1 cu. ft.
Virginia O'Neill was an architect in Stamford, Connecticut in the 1950's. The collection includes educational certificates, drawings, and plans for several residential projects.
Virginia O'Neill
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Virginia O'Neill Architectural Colelction was donated to the International Archive of Women in Architecture at the Special Collections in 2005.
Biographical Information
Virginia Brown O'Neill was born in 1923 in Stamford, Connecticut. She was an architect in the 1950's to the 1960's in Connecticut. Little is known about her projects. She retired to St. Petersburg, Florida and died in August 1999.
Scope and Content
The Virginia O'Neill architectural collection consists of personal materials and plans for several residential projects. Personal information includes a diploma from Stamford High School and two artistic drawings. Residential projects include architectural plans for several residential projects, including the Sawmill House, a six-room house and a vacation home in a hexagonal plan.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by material type.
Contents List
- Personal Papers (Folder 1)
  - Public School Certificate of Completion, 1937
  - Stamford High School Diploma, 1941
  - 2 Pencil sketch drawings, a girl and a solider, 1944
- Unidentified preliminary residential plans, 5 sets of sketches n.d. (Folder 2)
- Arrowhead House blueprints, 6 sheets of plans, details, and elevations, 1955 (Folder 3)
- Sawmill House, version 1 blueprints, 4 sheets including elevations, framing plan and foundation plan, 1957 (Folder 4)
- Windmill House preliminary drawings, 6 sheets including plans, elevations, sections and details, 1957 (Folder 5)
- Six Room House, 8 sheets including plans, elevations, sections and details, 1958 (Folder 6)
- Windmill House diazotype job prints, 10 sheets including landscape plan, plans, elevations, sections and details, 1959 (Folder 7)
- Roxbury School millwork drawings, 6 sheets 1959 (Folder 8)
- Vacation House/Hexagonal plan diazotypes, 10 sheets including elevations, sections, details and electrical plan, 1963 (Folder 9)
- Vacation House/Hexagonal plan tracings, 10 sheets including elevations, sections, details and electrical plan, 1963 (Folder 10)